

■ dmkavaler@ucdavis.edu | ★ www.kavaler.com

Overview.

I am experienced in data analysis, data mining, data gathering, statistical modeling, machine learning, metric design, and natural language processing. I have extensive experience in gathering data using R and Python to build both predictive and explanatory statistical models, and I am an adept programmer in multiple languages. My primary interests are in the fields of data analysis, data mining, empirical software engineering, and language processing.

Education _

University of California, Davis

Davis, California

Ph.D. Computer Science, 4.0 GPA

2013 - Present (Expected 2018)

University of California, Davis

Davis, California

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2009 - 2013

Publications

Elements of Socio-Technical Trust in GitHub: The Effects of Visibility, Expertise, Productivity, and Responsiveness.

Submitted ICSE 2018

DAVID KAVALER, PREM DEVANBU, VLADIMIR FILKOV

Exploiting Time and Subject Locality for Fast, Efficient, and Understandable Alert Triage

Accepted ICNC 2018

DAVID KAVALER, COREY HUDSON, MICHAEL BIERMA

Perceived Language Complexity in GitHub Issue Discussions and Their Effect on Issue Resolution

Accepted ASE 2017

DAVID KAVALER, SASHA SIROVICA, VINCENT HELLENDOORN, RAUL ARANOVICH, VLADIMIR FILKOV

Quality, Latency, and Amount of Stack Overflow Answers to Questions About Recent **Android APIs**

Submitted PLOS One

DAVID KAVALER, VLADIMIR FILKOV

Pending revisions

Stochastic Actor-Oriented Modeling for Studying Homophily and Social Influence in OSS **Projects**

Accepted to journal EMSE

DAVID KAVALER, VLADIMIR FILKOV

Invited to present at the International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016.

Using and Asking: APIs Used in the Android Market and Asked About in StackOverflow

Accepted SocInfo 2013

DAVID KAVALER, DARYL POSNETT, CLINT GIBLER, HAO CHEN, PREM DEVANBU, VLADIMIR FILKOV

· Best paper nominee.

Awards & Honors _

2015 Fellowship, UC Davis Graduate Group in Computer Science

2013 Fellowship, UC Davis Graduate Group in Computer Science

2013 Best Paper Nomination, International Conference on Social Informatics

Work Experience.

University of California, Davis

Davis, California

Sep. 2013 - Present

RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

Research assistant in the DECAL lab at UC Davis.

• Teaching assistant for multiple courses, including software engineering and introduction to object-oriented programming (C++).

Sandia National Laboratories

Livermore, California

CYBERSECURITY SUMMER RESEARCH INTERN

Jun. 2016 - Sep. 2016

• Worked towards various solutions for cybersecurity related problems. Pending publication.

Sensys Networks SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SUMMER INTERN

Berkeley, California Jun. 2010 - Sep. 2010

· Wrote code for a front-end in Actionscript to interface with wireless devices using a proprietary packet structure.

Skills_

Programming LanguagesR, Python, C/C++, C#, Java, LaTeX, JavascriptTools & FrameworksPostgreSQL, Node.js, Android, Unity, scikit-learn

References_

Vladimir Filkov filkov@cs.ucdavis.edu

Professor. Computer Science Department, UC Davis

Prem Devanbu devanbu@cs.ucdavis.edu

PROFESSOR. COMPUTER SCIENCE DEPARTMENT, UC DAVIS